1221 1<sup>st</sup> Ave Apt 2205 Seattle WA 98101

+1 (206) 953-3929 richa.shaurabh@gmail.com

<u>richasha.github.io/Portfolio</u> linkedin.com/in/richa-shaurabh

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 6 years of progressive software development experience and expertise in JavaScript, React.js, HTML, CSS, Rest APIs, SQL, etc. demonstrated in projects across Logistics & Supply Chain Management, Web development & Digital Marketing.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Tideworks Technology**

Feb 2018 – Present Seattle, WA, USA

Software Development Engineer

- Design & Development of large scale, multi-tiered web-based systems such as the company's proprietary Terminal Operating System: Mainsail, focused on growing terminal operations and shipping lines.
- Implementation of numerous key features using JavaScript, React.js, REST APIs & PL/SQL, that enable the customers of shipping terminals to view & manage cargo information, vessel movement, billing and truck documentation.
- Reviewing code of peer software developers on the team and refactoring it when needed to ensure software quality meets the highest standards of maintainability & extensibility.
- Communication with business analysts & stakeholders to understand & analyze business requirements for technical feasibility & design.
- Technical leadership & guidance to peer software developers during daily collaboration and via learning sessions on various advancements in frontend technologies such as React.js's new Context API, Updated Lifecycle methods, etc.
- Debugging & fixing of complex issues spanning large scale software systems & code bases.
- Development of clean & cohesive unit tests and organizing them into repeatable automated test suites.

Software Engineer

• Researched & evaluated LG's frontend framework "Enyo" against newer frameworks & technologies and helped devise a strategy for a

- Researched & evaluated LG's frontend framework "Enyo" against newer frameworks & technologies and helped devise a strategy for a
  major revamp to "Enact": LG's next generation React based JS framework
- Developed Enact framework components that can be used for developing native-quality, cross-device compatible HTML5 apps, as part of a team of developers distributed across US and India
- Recognized department-wide within a month of hire, for developing & optimizing the Camera & Gallery apps for LG Fx0 phone, on top of the Firefox Mobile OS's Gaia User Interface layer using Object Oriented JS.

Tech Mahindra

Nov 2013 – Apr 2015

Software Developer

Sydney, Australia & Bangalore, India

- Optus Mobile Network Coverage App Designed & developed a frontend application that showed network tower diagnosis information on a map to customers, using JavaScript, AngularJS & the OpenLayers library
- Also, developed the Customer Complaint Logging feature that can be used by customers to receive response from Optus Engineers.

**FLORET Media** 

Jan 2013 – Nov 2013

Web Developer

Bangalore, India

• As one of 10 developers at the startup firm, coordinated directly with several client organizations to analyze requirements and develop responsive websites to aid in their Digital marketing.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SASS, SCSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Testing Frameworks: Jest, Jasmine, Karma

Tools: SVN, Git, npm, Sublime Text, Firebase

OS Experience: MacOS, Windows

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Technology** from SRM University, Chennai, India **High School** from Patna Women's College, Patna, India

2008 - 2012 2008

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Epicodus Certified "Web & Mobile Development" Engineer [2017] Met all the certification requirements: JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL.
- Sports Awarded by the State government for winning in the Throwball league for the state of Bihar, India